R. Scott Vivilecchia

144 County Rd., Bourne, Massachusetts +1 617 678 4222 rscott@vi-vi.io linkedin.com/in/vi-vi-io https://vi-vi.io

A Visual Storyteller with over a decade of experience delivering poignant, strategy-driven content. I'm proficient in ideation, video editing, motion graphics, color grading, and sound design. With a distinctive blend of creative and technical expertise, I create video and digital experiences that educate, inform, and entertain.

Core Competencies

Pre-production:

- Research
- Strategy
- Script writing
- Story-boarding

Production:

- Directing
- Interviewing
- Studio and on-location set-up
- Videography/Photography

Post-production:

- Video editing
 - Special effects Chromakeying
- Color correction/grading
- Rotoscoping
- Motion graphics Sound design
- Motion tracking

Software: Adobe CC (Premiere, After Effects, Audition, Photoshop, Illustrator), Davinci Resolve, Red Giant, ProTools, Microsoft Office, Google Suite

Camera systems: Blackmagic, Canon, Panasonic, Sony

General skills: Graphic design, Typography, Illustration, Animation, Photo editing, Committed collaborator, Creative problem-solving, Strong attention to detail, Work independently, Al enhanced workflow, File management, Manage multiple projects

Work Experience

Designer, Filmmaker & Content Creator

VIVI Productions

- · Use a well-honed research process, meticulous strategic planning and thoughtful visual storytelling to create results-driven video and multimedia content for a diverse range of clients
- · Consult on strategy, trends and tech requirements for social media platforms and the web, leading to deeper engagement and increased call to action follow-through on campaigns
- Partner with clients and their subject matter experts throughout the entire product life cycle strategy, production, distribution, and evaluation
- Build consistent brand identities across channels, increasing recognition and content engagement

Video Production Specialist

2013 - 2019

2019 - Present

Voya Financial

- Collaborated with Fortune 500 and large government clients on award-winning educational videos that drove engagement with their unique employee benefit plans
- · Worked with the executive leadership team to plan, shoot, edit, and deliver engaging, meaningful video content that moved the needle on hundreds of sales pitches and marketing campaigns
- Contributed to the evolution of brand standards for video and web content

Creative Services Designer

2004 - 2013

Voya Financial, ING, CitiStreet

- · Designed impactful visual assets, including videos, web apps and PowerPoint presentations, to support sales efforts, leading to retirement plan conversions valued at Billions of dollars in assets under management, and positioning the company as a leader in the industry.
- · Collaborated with the Plan Participant Education team to develop a diverse library of client-branded web apps that led to a 12% average increase in retirement plan participation

Education